Guide to the Louis Lohr Martz Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Louis Lohr Martz Correspondence
1966-1996
YCAL MSS 881
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.04
(3 boxes)
Martz, Louis L. (Louis Lohr), 1913-2001
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: May 8 2000 Acquisition, May 30 2000 Acquisition, and May 2005 Acquisition.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Louis Lohr Martz (1913-2001) was Sterling Professor Emeritus of English at Yale University and acting director of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library (1972-1978).
Scope and Contents
The Louis Lohr Martz Correspondence comprises Martz's correspondence with the American and British writers Iris Murdoch, Richard Hugo, David Ignatow, James Laughlin, Owen Slavitt, Diane Wakoski, and Robert Penn Warren. Six page proofs of works by Murdoch are included, as are writings by other correspondents.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Louis Lohr Martz, 2000 and 2005.
American literature -- 20th Century; British literature -- 20th Century; Teachers -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Librarians -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Teachers -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- 20th Century; Librarians -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- 20th Century; Martz, Louis L. (Louis Lohr), 1913-2001; Murdoch, Iris, 1919-1999; Hugo, Richard, 1923-1982; Ignatow, David, 1914-1997; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; Slavitt, Owen; Wakoski, Diane, 1937-; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989
- May 2000 Acquisitions, 1969-1996; Series I; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Former call numbers: Uncat MSS 21 and Uncat MSS 32
  Arrangement
  This portion of the collection is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Hugo, Richard, 1980, undated (Box 1)
  - Ignatow, David, 1970-1994; 2 (Box 1)
    Contains correspondence, event invitations, and writings by Ingatow, including a typescript of the poetry volume Leaving the Door Open
  - Laughlin, James, 1992-1996; 2 (Box 1)
  - Slavitt, Owen, undated (Box 1)
  - Wakoski, Diane, 1969-1988 (Box 1)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1969-1970, 1980; 3 (Box 1)
- May 2005 Acquisition, 1966-1993; Series II; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 773
  This portion of the collection is arranged chronologically.
  - Iris Murdoch Writings
    - Fairly Honourable Defeat page proof, 1970-1970 (Box 2)
    - Henry and Cato page proofs, 1977-1977 (Box 2)
    - Sacred and Profane Love Machine page proofs, 1974-1974 (Box 2)
    - Three Arrows and the Servants and the Snow page proofs, with autograph manuscript letter from Murdoch to Martz, 1974-1974 (Box 2)
    - Time of the Angels page proofs, 1966-1966 (Box 2)
    - Unicorn galley proofs, undated (Box 3)
  - Iris Murdoch Printed Material
    - Clippings and articles on Murdoch, 1971-1993 (Box 3)